<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Literatures on</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/</link><description>Recent content in Literatures on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Resistance training for time efficiency, body composition, and maximum hypertrophy with Brad Schoenfeld</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/P-Resistance-Training-Patrick/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/P-Resistance-Training-Patrick/</guid><description>Why should we be resistance training? If you were to pick one form of exercise, it should be resistance training It gives all benefits of cardio in addition to: Muscle and bone strength Osteoporosis (esp for women) is a possibility with age Resistance training makes muscle pull on the bone, and strengthens the bone Weight bearing exercise strengthens bone, not other forms of exercise Cycling, swimming, and other forms of cardio does not help bone density, maybe running is ok to some extent Compound motions like squats, rows, presses, pushups are very helpful for bone density Even &amp;gt;70 yr olds see massive improvements in muscle strength when they start lifting, in 8-12 weeks, even if they have never training before.</description></item><item><title>How food powers your body</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/A-How-Food-Powers-Your-Body-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/A-How-Food-Powers-Your-Body-2022/</guid><description>Life is nothing but an electron looking for a place to rest
-Szent-Györgyi
What is the role of glucose in the body?</description></item><item><title>Turning music into a chore is how I became a musician</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/A-Turning-music-into-a-chore-is-how-I-became-a-musician/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/A-Turning-music-into-a-chore-is-how-I-became-a-musician/</guid><description>Summary The author of this article explains that by treating music making like a routine job that you do everyday, and putting in the time day after day without worrying about how good the output is, you can become really productive and consistent in making music, and produce high quality work.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/Building-Your-Brand-How-I-Reached-10k-Subscribers-in-6-Months/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/Building-Your-Brand-How-I-Reached-10k-Subscribers-in-6-Months/</guid><description>Building Your Brand: How I Reached 10k Subscribers in 6 Months Metadata Author: [[Jordan Cutler]] Full Title: Building Your Brand: How I Reached 10k Subscribers in 6 Months Category: #articles URL: https://careercutler.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/C-Pytorch-Day1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/C-Pytorch-Day1/</guid><description>Instructor: Ben Sherman from Weights and Biases
What are AI ML and DL? Deep learning is a specific form of machine learning.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/C-Pytorch-Day2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/C-Pytorch-Day2/</guid><description>Review A fully connected network does &amp;ldquo;non-deep&amp;rdquo; learning. It is only by connecting them to create multilayer perceptrons, or deep neural networks, that are capable of &amp;ldquo;deep&amp;rdquo; learning.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/Why-Engineers-Need-to-Write/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/Why-Engineers-Need-to-Write/</guid><description>Why Engineers Need to Write Metadata Author: [[Ryan Peterman]] Full Title: Why Engineers Need to Write Category: #articles URL: https://www.</description></item><item><title>A-Why City Life Makes Us Grumpy - by Robin Waldun</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/A-Why-City-Life-Makes-Us-Grumpy-by-Robin-Waldun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/A-Why-City-Life-Makes-Us-Grumpy-by-Robin-Waldun/</guid><description>Why City Life Makes Us Grumpy - by Robin Waldun #Omnivore
Read on Omnivore Read Original
Highlights Many of us can relate to this experience when we spend enough time in the metropolis: it sucks all the energy out of us.</description></item><item><title>A-Zettelkasten examples to get started</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/A-Zettelkasten-examples-to-get-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/A-Zettelkasten-examples-to-get-started/</guid><description>most zettelkasten resources explain the principles and assume you know how to design your implementation
this article helps you get started with zettelkasten Here is a possible workflow</description></item><item><title>Analysis and Design of Analog Integrated Circuits</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Meyer-1976-Ch4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Meyer-1976-Ch4/</guid><description>![[permanent/Need for Current Mirrors in Microelectronics]] Bias circuits designed with current sources tend to be more insensitive to power-supply and temperature variations For small currents, they tend to have a smaller on-chip footprint compared to resistor based techniques As active loads, they provide high impedance, enabling high gain in voltage amplifiers 4.</description></item><item><title>B-Forte-2022</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Forte-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Forte-2022/</guid><description>What is a second brain and how does it work? In today&amp;rsquo;s digital world we are inundated with information in the form of books, articles, podcasts, tweets and so on.</description></item><item><title>B-Newport-DeepWork</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Newport-DeepWork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Newport-DeepWork/</guid><description>Chapter Notes Introduction Newport suggests that the intense work practice of several people in history across multiple disciplines is responsible for their prolific contributions to their field.</description></item><item><title>Fitness toolkit: Protocol and Tools to Optimize Physical Health</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/P-Protocol-and-Tools-to-Optimize-Physical-Health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/P-Protocol-and-Tools-to-Optimize-Physical-Health/</guid><description>What is a [[Foundational Protocol]] for fitness? A foundational protocol for fitness is a workout routine that optimizes all protocol types (listed below).</description></item><item><title>Four Thousand Weeks: Time management for mortals</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Burkeman-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Burkeman-2021/</guid><description>What is the book about? Our time on this earth is limited to four thousand weeks, but our commitments, goals and desires far outstretch what is achievable in this short span of time.</description></item><item><title>Fundamentals of Microelectronics</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-razavi-microelec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-razavi-microelec/</guid><description>![[permanent/Need for Current Mirrors in Microelectronics]] The biasing provided to circuits should be independent of:
Voltage variation: Eg, the voltage from a battery drops as it discharges slowly Temperature variation: Eg, different environments / places have different ambient temperatures How does temperature affect the operation of circuits?</description></item><item><title>How to Take Smart Notes</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Ahrens-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Ahrens-2017/</guid><description>Chapter 1: Introduction [[permanent/Good workflow design]]
A good workflow design should:
be simple to use enable one to use the mind exclusively for thinking, learning, insight, and generation of ideas offload all other aspects of information storage and memory retrieval to an external system allow to jump in and out of lines of thought make work productive and fun [[permanent/Role of willpower in doing work]]</description></item><item><title>Introduction to PyTorch</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/C-Deep-Learning-with-PyTorch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/C-Deep-Learning-with-PyTorch/</guid><description>This course was offered to Qualcomm employees as Engineering Development
Terminology [[Artificial Intelligence]] : This is a field of study where machines mimic the intelligence of humans by learning and performing tasks based on the experience or data they are provided.</description></item><item><title>Operation and Modeling of the MOS Transistor</title><link>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Tsividis-1987-Ch1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.vsekar.com/literature/B-Tsividis-1987-Ch1/</guid><description>1.2 Semiconductors We will deal with silicon as semiconductor, and assume that it is in thermal equilibrium without any external influences.</description></item></channel></rss>